They came in peace, they left in chaos.
The Angry Birds Movie is a animation, adventure,
comedy film directed by Clay Kaytis.
An island populated entirely by happy, flightless birds or almost entirely.
In this paradise, Red, a bird with a temper problem, speedy Chuck,
and the volatile Bomb have always been outsiders.
But when the island is visited by mysterious green piggies, it’s up to
these unlikely outcasts to figure out what the pigs are up to.
Red (voice), played by Jason Sudeikis.
Chuck (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Bomb (voice), played by Danny McBride.
Matilda (voice), played by Maya Rudolph.
Leonard (voice), played by Bill Hader.
Mighty Eagle (voice), played by Peter Dinklage.
The Angry Birds Movie is a 2016 animated comedy film
based on the Angry Birds video game series.
It was directed by Clay Kaytis and Fergal Reilly, and written by Jon Vitti.
It features the voices of Jason Sudeikis, Josh Gad, Danny McBride, Maya Rudolph, Kate
McKinnon, Sean Penn, Tony Hale, Keegan-Michael Key, Bill Hader, and Peter Dinklage.
The film follows Red, an outcast on an island of anthropomorphic flightless birds, as he suspects a newly arrived crew of pigs, led by
Leonard, of plotting an evil plan, and attempts to put a stop to them with the help of his newfound friends Chuck and Bomb.
After the success of the Angry Birds Toons animated series, Rovio Entertainment, the
developer of the original video game, began work on a film adaptation.
The project was announced in December 2012.
The first image from the film was revealed in October 2014, with Sudeikis, Gad, McBride,
Hader, Rudolph, and Dinklage revealed to be part of its cast at the same time.
Rovio and Sony Pictures announced they would spend roughly €100 million on the marketing and distribution of
The Angry Birds Movie, becoming the most expensive Finnish-produced film up to that point.
Sony Pictures Imageworks was responsible for
handling animation services for the film.
The Angry Birds Movie was released in the United States on
May 20, 2016, by Sony Pictures Releasing.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $352 million.
A sequel, The Angry Birds Movie 2, was released in 2019, and a third
film, The Angry Birds Movie 3, is scheduled for 2026.
The film explores themes of island, pig, villain, eagle, rivalry.
The tone is lighthearted.